<?xml version="1.0"?>
<b:Sources SelectedStyle="" xmlns:b="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/bibliography" xmlns="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/bibliography"><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2025</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>techreport</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>Report</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>CROWDSTRIKE 2025 GLOBAL THREAT REPORT 2</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>Watch any nature program, and you’ll quickly discover what happens to animals that underestimate their adversaries. They become prey. The same principle applies in cybersecurity — the adversary is advancing so fast that you can’t afford to underestimate them. Our latest research demonstrates that adversaries are becoming more efficient, focused, and business-like in their approach — in many ways, more like the enterprise organizations they prey upon. That’s why our team of security analysts, experts, and authors chose “the enterprising adversary” as the theme for this year’s CrowdStrike Global Threat Report. Take generative artificial intelligence (genAI), for instance. Highly effective adversaries across all major categories — nation-state, eCrime, and hacktivist — have become early and avid adopters. The “force multiplier” impact of off-the-shelf chatbots has made genAI a popular addition to the global hacker toolbox. Along with legitimate organizations, easy access to commercial large language models (LLMs) is making adversaries more productive, too. It’s shortening their learning curve and development cycles, and it’s allowing them to increase the scale and pace of their activities. Though this report indicates that malicious use of AI is growing, it remains largely iterative and evolutionary at this point in time. Only occasionally does it manifest as an entirely novel use case. But it is still early days. At CrowdStrike, we aren’t waiting for threat actors to experience their next “aha” moment. We are accelerating our own use of AI techniques — from our foundational machine learning capabilities to our leading-edge generative and agentic AI models — to help our customers anticipate the next zero-day attacks in advance and proactively inoculate themselves against them. This is the essence of an AI-native approach to cyber defense. Unlike legacy systems — which are still relied upon by organizations globally — we don’t sit idle until an attack occurs before we can identify and stop it.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Institution>CrowdStrike, Inc.</b:Institution>
		<b:Tag>CrowdStrike2025</b:Tag>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>CrowdStrike</b:Last>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:ThesisType>Tech. rep.</b:ThesisType>
		<b:RefOrder>16</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2025</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>techreport</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>Report</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>2025 Data Breach Investigations Report (DBIR)</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>Hello, and welcome to Verizon’s 2025 Data Breach Investigations Report (DBIR)! We are thrilled to have you with us for this, the 18th annual installment of the DBIR. Whether you are a longtime reader or this is your first rodeo,1 you will find within the pages of this report a comprehensive examination of the recent state of cybercrime, along with insights on what threats your organization may likely face, who is behind them and what you can do to help protect yourself.

This year, the Verizon DBIR team analyzed 22,052 real-world security incidents, of which 12,195 were confirmed data breaches that occurred inside organizations of all sizes and types. This represents the highest number of breaches ever analyzed in a single report. These incidents and breaches were provided from the case files of the Verizon Threat Research Advisory Center (VTRAC) team, along with the generous support of our global contributors, and from publicly disclosed security incidents. Together, these attacks represent victims from 139 countries around the world.

Although the threat landscape can vary somewhat due to organizational size, mission and location, there are always certain overarching themes that seem to predominate our dataset regardless of any of these variables. This year is no exception. Possibly the most obvious and noteworthy among them is the role that third-party relationships play in how and why breaches occur.

While, to some extent, software vendors have long played a part in unintentionally increasing the attack surface for those who use their products and services, over the last two to three years, it has moved from the occasional (and typically minor to moderate) mishap to a much more widespread and insidious problem that can (and sometimes does) have a devastating effect on enterprises. In fact, this is the case to such an extent that it made the cover visualization for this year’s report,2 and you will find the subject woven throughout this document.

From this foundation, we explore in our “Results and analysis” section the growth of the well-known edge device vulnerability exploits that no cybersecurity professional could have failed to notice this year, along with the adverse effects those vulnerabilities can have on an organization’s security posture and how they can further complicate remediation efforts.

In our “Basic Web Application Attacks”3 section, we examine in some detail the issue of stolen credentials and application and programming interface (API) keys and what that ecosystem looks like. In addition, in our stolen credentials sidebar, we take a look at the infostealer malware problem and how it relates to bring your own device (BYOD) practices. Finally, we would be remiss if we did not mention the ever-present problem of ransomware that we discuss in our “System Intrusion” section,4 which grew yet again as a percentage of breaches, while at the same time declined with regard to median amount of ransom paid.

Return readers may notice some slight changes to the overall structure of this year’s report. Notably, we revisited the small- and medium-sized business section (and how smaller businesses compare to larger organizations), and the Public Administration industry snapshot was promoted to its own section (now “Public Sector” under “Focused analysis”).

And finally, as always, we wish to extend our warmest gratitude to our contributing organizations,5 without whose collaboration, civic mindedness and expertise this report could not be written, and to the outrageously talented VTRAC team. A very sincere thanks, as well, to our leader, Chris Novak, Vice President of Global Cybersecurity Solutions, for his continued support, insight and guidance.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Institution>Verizon</b:Institution>
		<b:Tag>Verizon2025</b:Tag>
		<b:URL>https://www.verizon.com/business/resources/reports/2025-dbir-data-breach-investigations-report.pdf</b:URL>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Verizon</b:Last>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:ThesisType>Tech. rep.</b:ThesisType>
		<b:RefOrder>5</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2024</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>AI-Enhanced Multimodal Search Engines for Cybersecurity Threat Detection</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>Cybersecurity threats have become increasingly sophisticated and pervasive in our interconnected digital world. As organizations rely more heavily on technology for their operations, the potential impact of security breaches has grown exponentially. Traditional threat detection methods, while still valuable, are struggling to keep pace with the evolving landscape of cyber-attacks. This has led to a growing interest in leveraging artificial intelligence (AI) and advanced search technologies to enhance cybersecurity defenses.

The field of AI has made significant strides in recent years, particularly in areas such as machine learning, deep learning, and natural language processing. These technologies have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in analyzing complex data patterns, identifying anomalies, and making predictions based on large datasets. When applied to cybersecurity, AI has the potential to dramatically improve threat detection accuracy, speed, and scalability.

Simultaneously, the concept of multimodal search has emerged as a powerful approach to information retrieval across diverse data types. Multimodal search engines can process and analyze various forms of data, including text, images, audio, and video, to provide more comprehensive and contextually relevant results. This capability is particularly relevant in cybersecurity, where threats can manifest across multiple data modalities.

This whitepaper explores the intersection of AI and multimodal search technologies in the context of cybersecurity threat detection. We posit that AI-enhanced multimodal search engines can significantly improve the ability to identify, analyze, and respond to cyber threats across diverse data types. By leveraging advanced machine learning algorithms and multimodal data fusion techniques, these systems can overcome many limitations of traditional threat detection methods and provide a more holistic view of the security landscape.

Throughout this paper, we will examine the current state of cybersecurity threat detection, explore the challenges and opportunities presented by multimodal data in security contexts, and delve into the core components and technologies that enable AI-enhanced multimodal search engines. We will also discuss practical applications of these systems in various cybersecurity domains, present case studies demonstrating their effectiveness, and consider the challenges and future research directions in this rapidly evolving field.

As cyber threats continue to grow in complexity and scale, it is crucial for security professionals, researchers, and organizations to explore innovative approaches to threat detection and response. AI-enhanced multimodal search engines represent a promising frontier in cybersecurity, offering the potential to significantly enhance our ability to protect digital assets and infrastructure in an increasingly hostile cyber environment Keywords: AI-enhanced multimodal search engines, Cybersecurity threat detection, Artificial intelligence, Machine learning, Deep learning, Natural language processing, Multimodal data, Network intrusion detection, Malware detection, Phishing and social engineering detection, Insider threat detection, Threat intelligence and hunting</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Ramalingam2024</b:Tag>
		<b:URL>https://ssrn.com/abstract=4903692</b:URL>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Ramalingam</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>Kumara</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Ganesh</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Sivasundar</b:Last>
						<b:First>Pattabiraman</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>July</b:Month>
		<b:RefOrder>28</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source><b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType><b:Title>AI-Enhanced Multimodal Search Engines for Cybersecurity Threat Detection</b:Title><b:Year>2024</b:Year><b:Month>7</b:Month><b:Author><b:Author><b:NameList><b:Person><b:Last>Ramalingam</b:Last><b:First>G.</b:First><b:Middle>K.</b:Middle></b:Person><b:Person><b:Last>Pattabiraman</b:Last><b:First>S.</b:First></b:Person></b:NameList></b:Author></b:Author><b:URL>https://papers.ssrn.com/abstract=4903692</b:URL><b:Tag>multim</b:Tag><b:Guid>{EA25BF7E-CBD3-4291-8194-C074E8614AF5}</b:Guid><b:RefOrder>31</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2023</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>techreport</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>Report</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>CyberInsecurity: The Cost of Monopoly</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>No software is perfect. This much is known from academia and every-day experience. Yet our industry knows how to design and deploy software so as to minimize security risks. However, when other goals are deemed more important than security, the consequences can be dangerous for software users and society at large.

Microsoft’s efforts to design its software in evermore complex ways so as to illegally shut out efforts by others to interoperate or compete with their products has succeeded. The monopoly product we all now rely on is thus both used by nearly everyone and riddled with flaws. A special burden rests upon Microsoft because of this ubiquity of its product, and we all need to be aware of the dangers that result from reliance upon such a widely used and essential product.

CCIA warned of the security dangers posed by software monopolies during the US antitrust proceeding against Microsoft in the mid and late 1990’s. We later urged the European Union to take measures to avoid a software “monoculture” that each day becomes more susceptible to computer viruses, Trojan Horses and other digital pathogens.

Our conclusions have now been confirmed and amplified by the appearance of this important report by leading authorities in the field of cybersecurity: Dan Geer, Rebecca ace, Peter Gutmann, Perry Metzger, John S. Quarterman, Charles Pfleeger, and Bruce Schneier.

CCIA and the report’s authors have arrived at their conclusions independently. Indeed, the views of the authors are their views and theirs alone. However, the growing consensus within the computer security community and industry at large is striking, and had become obvious: The presence of this single, dominant operating system in the hands of nearly all end users is inherently dangerous. The increased migration of that same operating system into the server world increases the danger even more. CCIA is pleased to have served as a catalyst and a publisher of the ideas of these distinguished authorities.

Over the years, Microsoft has deliberately added more and more features into its operating system in such a way that no end user could easily remove them. Yet, in so doing, the world’s PC operating system monopoly has created unacceptable levels of complexity to its software, in direct contradiction of the most basic tenets of computer security.

Microsoft, as the US trial record and experience has shown, has added these complex chunks of code to its operating system not because such programming complexity is necessary, but because it all but guarantees that computer makers, users and consumers will use Microsoft products rather than a competitor’s.

These competition related security problems have been with us, and getting worse, for years. The recent spate of virus attacks on the Internet is one more sign that we must realize the danger we are in. The report CyberInsecurity – The Cost of Monopoly is a wake up call that government and industry need to hear.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Institution>Computer &amp; Communications Industry Association Report</b:Institution>
		<b:Tag>Smith2023</b:Tag>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Smith</b:Last>
						<b:First>J.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Petrovic</b:Last>
						<b:First>P.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Rose</b:Last>
						<b:First>M.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Souza</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>De</b:Middle>
						<b:First>C.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Muller</b:Last>
						<b:First>L.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Nowak</b:Last>
						<b:First>B.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Martinez</b:Last>
						<b:First>J.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>September</b:Month>
		<b:ThesisType>Tech. rep.</b:ThesisType>
		<b:RefOrder>7</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source><b:Tag>Gee03</b:Tag><b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType><b:Guid>{21BC1410-6AF3-49C6-9B80-E2CE220DFA2F}</b:Guid><b:Author><b:Author><b:NameList><b:Person><b:Last>Geer</b:Last><b:First>D.</b:First></b:Person><b:Person><b:Last>Bace</b:Last><b:First>R.</b:First></b:Person><b:Person><b:Last>Gutmann</b:Last><b:First>P.</b:First></b:Person><b:Person><b:Last>Metzger</b:Last><b:First>P.</b:First></b:Person><b:Person><b:Last>Pfleeger</b:Last><b:First>C.</b:First><b:Middle>P.</b:Middle></b:Person><b:Person><b:Last>Quarterman</b:Last><b:First>J.</b:First><b:Middle>S.</b:Middle></b:Person><b:Person><b:Last>Schneier</b:Last><b:First>B.</b:First></b:Person></b:NameList></b:Author></b:Author><b:Title>Cyberinsecurity: The Cost of Monopoly</b:Title><b:Year>2023</b:Year><b:RefOrder>2</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:BIBTEX_Copyright>Creative Commons Attribution Non Commercial No Derivatives 4.0 International</b:BIBTEX_Copyright>
		<b:Year>2022</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Partially Trusting the Service Mesh Control Plane</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>Zero Trust is a novel cybersecurity model that focuses on continually evaluating trust to prevent the initiation and horizontal spreading of attacks. A cloud-native Service Mesh is an example of Zero Trust Architecture that can filter out external threats. However, the Service Mesh does not shield the Application Owner from internal threats, such as a rogue administrator of the cluster where their application is deployed. In this work, we are enhancing the Service Mesh to allow the definition and reinforcement of a Verifiable Configuration that is defined and signed off by the Application Owner. Backed by automated digital signing solutions and confidential computing technologies, the Verifiable Configuration allows changing the trust model of the Service Mesh, from the data plane fully trusting the control plane to partially trusting it. This lets the application benefit from all the functions provided by the Service Mesh (resource discovery, traffic management, mutual authentication, access control, observability), while ensuring that the Cluster Administrator cannot change the state of the application in a way that was not intended by the Application Owner.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Publisher>arXiv</b:Publisher>
		<b:Tag>Adam2022</b:Tag>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>Cryptography and Security (cs.CR), FOS: Computer and information sciences, FOS: Computer and information sciences</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:URL>http://arxiv.org/abs/2210.12610</b:URL>
		<b:DOI>10.48550/ARXIV.2210.12610</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Adam</b:Last>
						<b:First>Constantin</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Adebayo</b:Last>
						<b:First>Abdulhamid</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Franke</b:Last>
						<b:First>Hubertus</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Snible</b:Last>
						<b:First>Edward</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Feldman-Fitzthum</b:Last>
						<b:First>Tobin</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Cadden</b:Last>
						<b:First>James</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Jean-Louis</b:Last>
						<b:First>Nerla</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>October</b:Month>
		<b:RefOrder>13</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:BIBTEX_Series>Communications in computer and information science</b:BIBTEX_Series>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>inbook</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:Comments>Includes author index</b:Comments>
		<b:SourceType>BookSection</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Deep Reinforcement Learning for Cybersecurity Threat Detection and Protection: A Review</b:Title>
		<b:Publisher>Springer International Publishing</b:Publisher>
		<b:BookTitle>Secure Knowledge Management In The Artificial Intelligence Era</b:BookTitle>
		<b:URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-97532-6_4#citeas</b:URL>
		<b:Year>2022</b:Year>
		<b:Volume>1549</b:Volume>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>The cybersecurity threat landscape has lately become overly complex. Threat actors leverage weaknesses in the network and endpoint security in a very coordinated manner to perpetuate sophisticated attacks that could bring down the entire network and many critical hosts in the network. Increasingly advanced deep and machine learning-based solutions have been used in threat detection and protection. The application of these techniques has been reviewed well in the scientific literature. Deep Reinforcement Learning has shown great promise in developing AI-based solutions for areas that had earlier required advanced human cognizance. Different techniques and algorithms under deep reinforcement learning have shown great promise in applications ranging from games to industrial processes where it is claimed to augment systems with general AI capabilities. These algorithms have recently also been used in cybersecurity, especially in threat detection and endpoint protection, where these are showing state-of-the-art results. Unlike supervised machine and deep learning, deep reinforcement learning is used in more diverse ways and are empowering many innovative applications in the threat defense landscape. However, there does not exist any comprehensive review of these unique applications and accomplishments. Therefore, in this paper, we intend to fill this gap and provide a comprehensive review of the different applications of deep reinforcement learning in cybersecurity threat detection and protection.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Sewak2022</b:Tag>
		<b:DOI>10.1007/978-3-030-97532-6_4</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Sewak</b:Last>
						<b:First>Mohit</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Sahay</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>K.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Sanjay</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Rathore</b:Last>
						<b:First>Hemant</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
			<b:Editor>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Krishnan</b:Last>
						<b:First>Ram</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Rao</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>Raghav</b:Middle>
						<b:First>H.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Sahay</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>K.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Sanjay</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Samtani</b:Last>
						<b:First>Sagar</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Zhao</b:Last>
						<b:First>Ziming</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Editor>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>51-72</b:Pages>
		<b:Month>February</b:Month>
		<b:Number>1549</b:Number>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISBN: 9783030975326 ISSN: 1865-0937</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:ConferenceName>Secure Knowledge Management In The Artificial Intelligence Era</b:ConferenceName>
		<b:City>Cham</b:City>
		<b:StateProvince>Switzerland</b:StateProvince>
		<b:RefOrder>26</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2020</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>techreport</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>Report</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Zero Trust Architecture</b:Title>
		<b:Institution>National Institute of Standards and Technology</b:Institution>
		<b:Tag>Rose2020</b:Tag>
		<b:URL>https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.800-207.pdf</b:URL>
		<b:DOI>10.6028/NIST.SP.800-207</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Rose</b:Last>
						<b:First>Scott</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Borchert</b:Last>
						<b:First>Oliver</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Mitchell</b:Last>
						<b:First>Stu</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Connelly</b:Last>
						<b:First>Sean</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>August</b:Month>
		<b:ThesisType>Tech. rep.</b:ThesisType>
		<b:RefOrder>15</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2020</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>book</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Security engineering</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>Now that there's software in everything, how can you make anything secure? Understand how to engineer dependable systems with this newly updated classic In Security Engineering: A Guide to Building Dependable Distributed Systems, Third Edition Cambridge University professor Ross Anderson updates his classic textbook and teaches readers how to design, implement, and test systems to withstand both error and attack. This book became a best-seller in 2001 and helped establish the discipline of security engineering. By the second edition in 2008, underground dark markets had let the bad guys specialize and scale up; attacks were increasingly on users rather than on technology. The book repeated its success by showing how security engineers can focus on usability. Now the third edition brings it up to date for 2020. As people now go online from phones more than laptops, most servers are in the cloud, online advertising drives the Internet and social networks have taken over much human interaction, many patterns of crime and abuse are the same, but the methods have evolved. Ross Anderson explores what security engineering means in 2020, including: How the basic elements of cryptography, protocols, and access control translate to the new world of phones, cloud services, social media and the Internet of Things Who the attackers are - from nation states and business competitors through criminal gangs to stalkers and playground bullies What they do - from phishing and carding through SIM swapping and software exploits to DDoS and fake news Security psychology, from privacy through ease-of-use to deception The economics of security and dependability - why companies build vulnerable systems and governments look the other way How dozens of industries went online - well or badly.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</b:Publisher>
		<b:Tag>Anderson2020</b:Tag>
		<b:Edition>Third edition</b:Edition>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Anderson</b:Last>
						<b:First>Ross.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
			<b:Editor>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Anderson</b:Last>
						<b:First>Ross</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Editor>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>1232</b:Pages>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISBN: 9781119642787</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:City>Indianapolis</b:City>
		<b:RefOrder>1</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:BIBTEX_Copyright>arXiv.org perpetual, non-exclusive license</b:BIBTEX_Copyright>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:Comments>arXiv:2006.11239</b:Comments>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Denoising Diffusion Probabilistic Models</b:Title>
		<b:Publisher>arXiv</b:Publisher>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>Machine Learning (cs.LG), Machine Learning (stat.ML), FOS: Computer and information sciences</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:URL>http://arxiv.org/abs/2006.11239</b:URL>
		<b:Year>2020</b:Year>
		<b:Volume>33</b:Volume>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>We present high quality image synthesis results using diffusion probabilistic models, a class of latent variable models inspired by considerations from nonequilibrium thermodynamics. Our best results are obtained by training on a weighted variational bound designed according to a novel connection between diffusion probabilistic models and denoising score matching with Langevin dynamics, and our models naturally admit a progressive lossy decompression scheme that can be interpreted as a generalization of autoregressive decoding. On the unconditional CIFAR10 dataset, we obtain an Inception score of 9.46 and a state-of-the-art FID score of 3.17. On 256x256 LSUN, we obtain sample quality similar to ProgressiveGAN. Our implementation is available at https://github.com/hojonathanho/diffusion</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Ho2020</b:Tag>
		<b:DOI>10.48550/ARXIV.2006.11239</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Ho</b:Last>
						<b:First>Jonathan</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Jain</b:Last>
						<b:First>Ajay</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Abbeel</b:Last>
						<b:First>Pieter</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>6840-6851</b:Pages>
		<b:Month>December</b:Month>
		<b:JournalName>arXiv preprint arXiv:2006.11239</b:JournalName>
		<b:RefOrder>27</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2018</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>book</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:Comments>Includes bibliographical references and index</b:Comments>
		<b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Networks</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>The study of networks, including computer networks, social networks, and biological networks, has attracted enormous interest in recent years. The rise of the Internet and the wide availability of inexpensive computers have made it possible to gather and analyse network data on an unprecendented scale, and the development of new theoretical tools has allowed us to extract knowledge from networks of many different kinds. The study of networks is broadly interdisciplinary and developments have occurred in many fields, including mathematics, physics, computer and information sciences, biology, and the social science. This book brings together the most important breakthroughts in each of these fields and presents them in a unified fashion, highlighting the strong interconnections between work in different areas. Topics covered include the measurement of networks; methods for analysing network data, including methods developed in physics, statistics, and sociology; fundamentals of graph theory; computer algorithms, including spectral algorithms and community detection; mathematical models of networks such as random graph models and generative models; and models of processes taking place on networks.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Publisher>Oxford University Press</b:Publisher>
		<b:Tag>Newman2018</b:Tag>
		<b:Edition>Second edition</b:Edition>
		<b:DOI>10.1093/oso/9780198805090.001.0001</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Newman</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>E. J.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Mark</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>July</b:Month>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISBN: 9780192527493</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:City>Oxford</b:City>
		<b:RefOrder>8</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:BIBTEX_Copyright>arXiv.org perpetual, non-exclusive license</b:BIBTEX_Copyright>
		<b:Year>2017</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Semi-Supervised Classification with Graph Convolutional Networks</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>We present a scalable approach for semi-supervised learning on graph-structured data that is based on an efficient variant of convolutional neural networks which operate directly on graphs. We motivate the choice of our convolutional architecture via a localized first-order approximation of spectral graph convolutions. Our model scales linearly in the number of graph edges and learns hidden layer representations that encode both local graph structure and features of nodes. In a number of experiments on citation networks and on a knowledge graph dataset we demonstrate that our approach outperforms related methods by a significant margin.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Publisher>arXiv</b:Publisher>
		<b:Tag>Kipf2017</b:Tag>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>Machine Learning (cs.LG), Machine Learning (stat.ML), FOS: Computer and information sciences</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:URL>http://arxiv.org/abs/1609.02907</b:URL>
		<b:DOI>10.48550/ARXIV.1609.02907</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Kipf</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>N.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Thomas</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Welling</b:Last>
						<b:First>Max</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>February</b:Month>
		<b:Day>9</b:Day>
		<b:RefOrder>25</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2017</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Series>Adaptive computation and machine learning</b:BIBTEX_Series>
		<b:Volume>19</b:Volume>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>book</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:Comments>Includes bibliographical references and index</b:Comments>
		<b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Deep learning</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>Introduction – I. Applied math and machine learning basics. Linear algebra – Probability and information theory – Numerical computation – Machine learning basics – II. Deep networks : modern practices. Deep feedforward networks – Regularization for deep learning – Optimization for training deep models – Convolutional networks – Sequence modeling : recurrent and recursive nets – Practical methodology – Applications – III. Deep learning research. Linear factor models – Autoencoders – Representation learning – Structured probabilistic models for deep learning – Monte Carlo methods – Confronting the partition function – Approximate inference – Deep generative models.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Publisher>The MIT Press</b:Publisher>
		<b:Tag>Goodfellow2017</b:Tag>
		<b:URL>https://mitpress.mit.edu/9780262035613/deep-learning/</b:URL>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Goodfellow</b:Last>
						<b:First>Ian.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Bengio</b:Last>
						<b:First>Yoshua.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Courville</b:Last>
						<b:First>Aaron.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
			<b:Editor>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Courville</b:Last>
						<b:First>Aaron</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Bengio</b:Last>
						<b:First>Yoshua</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Editor>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>775</b:Pages>
		<b:JournalName>Genetic Programming and Evolvable Machines</b:JournalName>
		<b:Number>1–2</b:Number>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISBN: 9780262035613 ISSN: 1573-7632</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:City>Cambridge</b:City>
		<b:StateProvince>Massachusetts</b:StateProvince>
		<b:RefOrder>9</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2016</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>techreport</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>Report</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>No More Chewy Centers: The Zero Trust Model Of Information Security</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>There’s an old saying in information security: “We want our network to be like an M&amp;M, with a hard crunchy outside and a soft chewy center.” For today’s digital business, this perimeter-based security model is ineffective against malicious insiders and targeted attacks. Security and risk (S&amp;R) pros must eliminate the soft chewy center and make security ubiquitous throughout the digital business ecosystem — not just at the perimeter. In 2009, we developed a new information security model, called the Zero Trust Model, which has gained widespread acceptance and adoption. This report explains the vision and key concepts of the model. This is an update of a previously published report; Forrester reviews and updates it periodically for continued relevance and accuracy.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Institution>Forrester Research, Inc.</b:Institution>
		<b:Tag>Kindervag2016</b:Tag>
		<b:URL>https://www.forrester.com/report/No-More-Chewy-Centers-The-Zero-Trust-Model-Of-Information-Security/RES56682</b:URL>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Kindervag</b:Last>
						<b:First>John</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>May</b:Month>
		<b:ThesisType>Tech. rep.</b:ThesisType>
		<b:RefOrder>3</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source><b:Tag>MIJ15</b:Tag><b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType><b:Guid>{8C67220E-D053-42D8-ABCD-57185365560D}</b:Guid><b:Author><b:Author><b:NameList><b:Person><b:Last>Jordan</b:Last><b:First>M.</b:First><b:Middle>I.</b:Middle></b:Person><b:Person><b:Last>Mitchell</b:Last><b:First>T.</b:First><b:Middle>M.</b:Middle></b:Person></b:NameList></b:Author></b:Author><b:Title>Machine learning: Trends, perspectives, and prospects</b:Title><b:Year>2015</b:Year><b:Volume>349</b:Volume><b:Pages>255-260</b:Pages><b:DOI>10.1126/science.aaa8415</b:DOI><b:JournalName>Science</b:JournalName><b:RefOrder>24</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source><b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType><b:Title>Nonlinear systems</b:Title><b:Year>2014</b:Year><b:StandardNumber>9781292039213</b:StandardNumber><b:Publisher>Pearson Education Limited</b:Publisher><b:Author><b:Author><b:NameList><b:Person><b:First>Hassan K..</b:First><b:Last>Khalil</b:Last></b:Person></b:NameList></b:Author></b:Author><b:URL>https://dokumen.pub/nonlinear-systems-third-edition-1292039213-1269374508-9781292039213-9781269374507.html</b:URL><b:Tag>nonlinear-systems</b:Tag><b:RefOrder>17</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source><b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType><b:Title>Ethical theory and business</b:Title><b:Year>2014</b:Year><b:StandardNumber>9781269374507</b:StandardNumber><b:Publisher>Pearson Education Limited</b:Publisher><b:Pages>608</b:Pages><b:Author><b:Author><b:NameList><b:Person><b:First>Denis Gordon.</b:First><b:Last>Arnold</b:Last></b:Person><b:Person><b:First>Tom L..</b:First><b:Last>Beauchamp</b:Last></b:Person><b:Person><b:First>Norman E..</b:First><b:Last>Bowie</b:Last></b:Person></b:NameList></b:Author></b:Author><b:Tag>ethical-theory-and-business</b:Tag><b:RefOrder>29</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source><b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType><b:Title>Cooperative Control of Multi-Agent Systems</b:Title><b:Year>2014</b:Year><b:StandardNumber>978-1-4471-5573-7</b:StandardNumber><b:StandardNumber>0899-5885</b:StandardNumber><b:Publisher>Springer London</b:Publisher><b:Pages>307</b:Pages><b:Author><b:Author><b:NameList><b:Person><b:First>Frank L.</b:First><b:Last>Lewis</b:Last></b:Person><b:Person><b:First>Hongwei</b:First><b:Last>Zhang</b:Last></b:Person><b:Person><b:First>Kristian</b:First><b:Last>Hengster-Movric</b:Last></b:Person><b:Person><b:First>Abhijit</b:First><b:Last>Das</b:Last></b:Person></b:NameList></b:Author></b:Author><b:URL>https://link.springer.com/10.1007/978-1-4471-5574-4</b:URL><b:City>London</b:City><b:Tag>cooperative-control-of-multi-agent-systems</b:Tag><b:RefOrder>30</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2013</b:Year>
		<b:Volume>39</b:Volume>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Cyber-physical security metric inference in smart grid critical infrastructures based on system administrators’ responsive behavior</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>To protect complex power-grid control networks, efficient security assessment techniques are required. However, efficiently making sure that calculated security measures match the expert knowledge is a challenging endeavor. In this paper, we present EliMet, a framework that combines information from different sources and estimates the extent to which a control network meets its security objective. Initially, EliMet passively observes system operators' online reactive behavior against security incidents, and accordingly refines the calculated security measure values. To make the values comply with the expert knowledge, EliMet actively queries operators regarding those states for which sufficient information was not gained during the passive observation. Finally, EliMet makes use of the estimated security measure values for predictive situational awareness by ranking potential cyber-physical contingencies that the security administrators should plan for upfront. Our experimental results show that EliMet can optimally make use of prior knowledge as well as automated inference techniques to minimize human involvement and efficiently deduce the expert knowledge regarding individual states of that particular system.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Publisher>Elsevier BV</b:Publisher>
		<b:Tag>Zonouz2013</b:Tag>
		<b:URL>https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0167404813000941</b:URL>
		<b:DOI>10.1016/j.cose.2013.07.003</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Zonouz</b:Last>
						<b:First>Saman</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Haghani</b:Last>
						<b:First>Parisa</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>190-200</b:Pages>
		<b:Month>November</b:Month>
		<b:JournalName>Computers &amp; Security</b:JournalName>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISSN: 0167-4048</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:RefOrder>4</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source><b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType><b:Title>Attack Detection and Identification in Cyber-Physical Systems</b:Title><b:Year>2013</b:Year><b:Month>11</b:Month><b:StandardNumber>0018-9286</b:StandardNumber><b:Publisher>IEEE</b:Publisher><b:Pages>2715-2729</b:Pages><b:JournalName>IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control</b:JournalName><b:Volume>58</b:Volume><b:Issue>11</b:Issue><b:Author><b:Author><b:NameList><b:Person><b:First>Fabio</b:First><b:Last>Pasqualetti</b:Last></b:Person><b:Person><b:First>Florian</b:First><b:Last>Dorfler</b:Last></b:Person><b:Person><b:First>Francesco</b:First><b:Last>Bullo</b:Last></b:Person></b:NameList></b:Author></b:Author><b:URL>http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6545301/</b:URL><b:Tag>ystems</b:Tag><b:Guid>{7CD89350-5C2B-448F-8569-E8A863026956}</b:Guid><b:RefOrder>20</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2012</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Series>Adaptive computation and machine learning series</b:BIBTEX_Series>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>book</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:Comments>Am Ende des Preface (Seite XXIX): "First printing: August 2012. Second printing: November 2012 (same as first). Third printing: February 2013 (fixed some typos). Fourth printing: August 2013 (fixed many typos)"</b:Comments>
		<b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Machine learning : a probabilistic perspective</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>"This textbook offers a comprehensive and self-contained introduction to the field of machine learning, based on a unified, probabilistic approach. The coverage combines breadth and depth, offering necessary background material on such topics as probability, optimization, and linear algebra as well as discussion of recent developments in the field, including conditional random fields, L1 regularization, and deep learning. The book is written in an informal, accessible style, complete with pseudo-code for the most important algorithms. All topics are copiously illustrated with color images and worked examples drawn from such application domains as biology, text processing, computer vision, and robotics. Rather than providing a cookbook of different heuristic methods, the book stresses a principled model-based approach, often using the language of graphical models to specify models in a concise and intuitive way. Almost all the models described have been implemented in a MATLAB software package–PMTK (probabilistic modeling toolkit)–that is freely available online"–Back cover. Contents – Preface – 1 Introduction – 2 Probability – 3 Generative Models for Discrete Data – 4 Gaussian Models – 5 Bayesian Statistics – 6 Frequentist Statistics – 7 Linear Regression – 8 Logistic Regression – 9 Generalized Linear Models and the Exponential Family – 10 Directed Graphical Models (Bayes Nets) – 11 Mixture Models and the EM Algorithm – 12 Latent Linear Models – 13 Sparse Linear Models – 14 Kernels – 15 Gaussian Processes – 16 Adaptive Basis Function Models – 17 Markov and Hidden Markov Models – 18 State Space Models</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Publisher>MIT Press</b:Publisher>
		<b:Tag>Murphy2012</b:Tag>
		<b:Edition>4. print. (fixed many typos)</b:Edition>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Murphy</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>P.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Kevin</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>1067</b:Pages>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISBN: 9780262018029</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:City>Cambridge, Mass. [u.a.]</b:City>
		<b:RefOrder>23</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source><b:Tag>Ami11</b:Tag><b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType><b:Guid>{6B6E3781-D872-491C-9E22-54FEFA0D0CD3}</b:Guid><b:Author><b:Author><b:NameList><b:Person><b:Last>Amin</b:Last><b:First>Saurabh</b:First></b:Person></b:NameList></b:Author></b:Author><b:Title>On Cyber Security for Networked Control Systems</b:Title><b:Year>2011</b:Year><b:Publisher>Berkeley</b:Publisher><b:RefOrder>19</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source><b:Tag>Som10</b:Tag><b:SourceType>ConferenceProceedings</b:SourceType><b:Guid>{6855EBAC-B784-41F8-B3FA-9A56FFEFA019}</b:Guid><b:Author><b:Author><b:NameList><b:Person><b:Last>Sommer</b:Last><b:First>Robin</b:First></b:Person><b:Person><b:Last>Paxson</b:Last><b:First>Vern</b:First></b:Person></b:NameList></b:Author></b:Author><b:Title>Outside the Closed World: On Using Machine Learning for Network Intrusion Detection</b:Title><b:Year>2010</b:Year><b:Pages>315-316</b:Pages><b:Publisher>IEEE</b:Publisher><b:YearAccessed>2026</b:YearAccessed><b:MonthAccessed>2</b:MonthAccessed><b:DayAccessed>24</b:DayAccessed><b:URL>http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/5504793/</b:URL><b:DOI>10.1109/SP.2010.25</b:DOI><b:ConferenceName>2010 IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy</b:ConferenceName><b:RefOrder>10</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source><b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType><b:Title>Modern Control Engineering</b:Title><b:Year>2010</b:Year><b:Publisher>Pearson, Upper Saddle River</b:Publisher><b:Author><b:Author><b:NameList><b:Person><b:First>Katsuhiko</b:First><b:Last>Ogata</b:Last></b:Person></b:NameList></b:Author></b:Author><b:URL>https://www.scirp.org/reference/referencespapers?referenceid=2336381</b:URL><b:Edition>5th Edition</b:Edition><b:Tag>modern-control-engineering</b:Tag><b:RefOrder>18</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2009</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Series>SpringerLink</b:BIBTEX_Series>
		<b:Volume>5700</b:Volume>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>inbook</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>BookSection</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Structural Operational Semantics for Weighted Transition Systems</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>Weighted transition systems are defined, parametrized by a commutative monoid of weights. These systems are further understood as coalgebras for functors of a specific form. A general rule format for the SOS specification of weighted systems is obtained via the coalgebraic approach of Turi and Plotkin. Previously known formats for labelled transition systems (GSOS) and stochastic systems (SGSOS) appear as special cases.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Publisher>Springer, Berlin</b:Publisher>
		<b:Tag>Klin2009</b:Tag>
		<b:BookTitle>Semantics and Algebraic Specification</b:BookTitle>
		<b:URL>http://link.springer.com/10.1007/978-3-642-04164-8_7</b:URL>
		<b:DOI>10.1007/978-3-642-04164-8_7</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Klin</b:Last>
						<b:First>Bartek</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
			<b:Editor>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Palsberg</b:Last>
						<b:First>J.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Editor>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>121-139</b:Pages>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISBN: 9783642041648 ISSN: 1611-3349</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:ConferenceName>Semantics and Algebraic Specification</b:ConferenceName>
		<b:City>Berlin</b:City>
		<b:StateProvince>Heidelberg</b:StateProvince>
		<b:RefOrder>14</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2002</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>book</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:Comments>Literaturverz. S. 993 - 1062</b:Comments>
		<b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Computer security</b:Title>
		<b:Publisher>Addison-Wesley</b:Publisher>
		<b:Tag>Bishop2002</b:Tag>
		<b:Edition>10. print.</b:Edition>
		<b:URL>https://www.informit.com/store/computer-security-art-and-science-9780201440997</b:URL>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Bishop</b:Last>
						<b:First>Matt</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>December</b:Month>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISBN: 9780201440997</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:City>Boston [u.a.]</b:City>
		<b:RefOrder>6</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2000</b:Year>
		<b:Volume>86</b:Volume>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Epidemic spreading in scale-free networks</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>The Internet, as well as many other networks, has a very complex connectivity recently modeled by the class of scale-free networks. This feature, which appears to be very efficient for a communications network, favors at the same time the spreading of computer viruses. We analyze real data from computer virus infections and find the average lifetime and prevalence of viral strains on the Internet. We define a dynamical model for the spreading of infections on scale-free networks, finding the absence of an epidemic threshold and its associated critical behavior. This new epidemiological framework rationalize data of computer viruses and could help in the understanding of other spreading phenomena on communication and social networks.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Publisher>American Physical Society (APS)</b:Publisher>
		<b:Tag>Pastor-Satorras2000</b:Tag>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>0550+q,0570Ln,PACS numbers</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:URL>http://arxiv.org/abs/cond-mat/0010317 http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevLett.86.3200</b:URL>
		<b:DOI>10.1103/physrevlett.86.3200</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Pastor-Satorras</b:Last>
						<b:First>Romualdo</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Vespignani</b:Last>
						<b:First>Alessandro</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>3200–3203</b:Pages>
		<b:Month>October</b:Month>
		<b:JournalName>Physical Review Letters</b:JournalName>
		<b:Number>14</b:Number>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISSN: 1079-7114</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:RefOrder>22</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source><b:Tag>Haf96</b:Tag><b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType><b:Guid>{06C2E773-9EF0-4DDC-B7D3-10495C8B94A2}</b:Guid><b:Title>Where wizards stay up late : the origins of the Internet</b:Title><b:Year>1996</b:Year><b:Publisher>Simon &amp; Schuster: Riverside</b:Publisher><b:Author><b:Author><b:NameList><b:Person><b:Last>Hafner</b:Last><b:First>Katie</b:First></b:Person><b:Person><b:Last>Lyon</b:Last><b:First>Matthew.</b:First></b:Person></b:NameList></b:Author><b:Editor><b:NameList><b:Person><b:Last>Lyon</b:Last><b:First>Matthew</b:First></b:Person></b:NameList></b:Editor></b:Author><b:RefOrder>12</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source><b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType><b:Title>Applied Nonlinear Dynamics</b:Title><b:Year>1991</b:Year><b:StandardNumber>9780130408907</b:StandardNumber><b:StandardNumber>0899-5885</b:StandardNumber><b:Pages>231-236</b:Pages><b:JournalName>Prentice-Hall</b:JournalName><b:Volume>9</b:Volume><b:Issue>2</b:Issue><b:Author><b:Author><b:NameList><b:Person><b:Last>Slotine</b:Last><b:First>J.J.E.</b:First></b:Person><b:Person><b:Last>Li</b:Last><b:First>Weiping</b:First></b:Person></b:NameList></b:Author></b:Author><b:URL>http://ahs.idm.oclc.org/login?url=http://search.ebscohost.com/login.aspx?direct=true&amp;db=rzh&amp;AN=107335910&amp;site=ehost-live</b:URL><b:Tag>appliednonlineardynamics</b:Tag><b:Guid>{80574FFE-A50E-499D-BBE0-D753A8E4F91C}</b:Guid><b:RefOrder>21</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>1974</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>THE PROTECTION OF INFORMATION IN COMPUTER SYSTEMS</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>The enclosed paper is a tutorial prepared by invitation for possible publication in the Proceedings of the IEEE, and for use in M.I.T. subject 6.033, "Information Systems". Any comments you might have would be welcomed. We are particularly interested in verifying the accuracy of the many historical attributions which appear throughout the paper, and adding any which have been omitted. Of course comments on the technical content are also of interest. Abstract-This tutorial paper explores the mechanics of protecting information stored in computer systems. It begins by discussing desired functions, design principles, and examples of elementary protection and user authentication mechanisms. The second major part examines in depth the principles of modern descriptor-based protection architectures and the relation between capability systems and access-control-list systems. This discussion ends with a.brief analysis of protected subsystems and protected objects. The last part of the paper reviews the state of the art and current research problems and also provides suggestions for further reading. The authors are with Project MAC and the Computer Science section of the</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Saltzer1974</b:Tag>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>OneTouch</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:URL>https://www.cs.virginia.edu/ evans/cs551/saltzer/</b:URL>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Saltzer</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>H.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>J.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Schroeder</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>D.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>M.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Saltzer</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>H.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Jerome</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Schroeder</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>D.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Michael</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>October</b:Month>
		<b:JournalName>Fourth ACM Symposium on Operating System Principles</b:JournalName>
		<b:RefOrder>11</b:RefOrder></b:Source></b:Sources>
