<?xml version="1.0"?>
<b:Sources SelectedStyle="" xmlns:b="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/bibliography" xmlns="http://schemas.openxmlformats.org/officeDocument/2006/bibliography"><b:Source>
		<b:Issue>1</b:Issue>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>inproceedings</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>ConferenceProceedings</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Synthetic network traffic generation for intrusion detection systems: a systematic literature review</b:Title>
		<b:Publisher>de Limoges, Université</b:Publisher>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>Generative AI,Networking,Networking Generative AI Traffic Generation,Photovoltaïques Organiques (OPVs),Simultaneous Lightwave Information and Power Trans,Traffic Generation,Transfert Simultané d’Information et d’Énergie par,Visible Light Communication (VLC)</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:BookTitle>ANUBIS 2025 - 1st International Workshop on Assessment with New methodologies</b:BookTitle>
		<b:URL>https://hal.science/hal-05379236 https://hal.science/hal-05379236/document</b:URL>
		<b:Department>Université de Limoges</b:Department>
		<b:Year>2025</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>Network data can be difficult to collect due to privacy and confidentiality reasons. For these reasons, network datasets are typically created with controlled environments called testbeds. However, these datasets are regularly criticized for their limited size, class imbalance, obsolescence, and lack of actual user activity. Following the rapid development of generative artificial intelligence, new methods have been applied to synthetic network traffic generation without emulation or simulation. This systematic literature review assesses the current state of synthetic network traffic generation for intrusion detection systems.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Gimenez2025</b:Tag>
		<b:DOI>10.34894/VQ1DJA</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Gimenez</b:Last>
						<b:First>Pierre-François</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>1–18</b:Pages>
		<b:Month>September</b:Month>
		<b:ConferenceName>ANUBIS 2025 - 1st International Workshop on Assessment with New methodologies</b:ConferenceName>
		<b:RefOrder>4</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2025</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>inproceedings</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>ConferenceProceedings</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Synthetic data generation for cybersecurity applications: an exploratory study of gan models</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>1 Cyeersecurity systems rely heavily on high-quality datasets to train effective intrusion detection mechanisms and malware classification models. However, real-world cybersecurity datasets often face challenges such as limited availability, high annotation costs, privacy risks, and imbalanced class distributions. Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) have emerged as a promising approach for generating synthetic data that mimics real datasets' statistical properties and structural patterns while preserving privacy. This paper explores multiple GAN variants: CGAN, CycleGAN, BiGAN, DGAN, LSGAN, Tabular GANs, WGAN, WGAN-GP, SeqGAN, and TextGAN, in the context of cybersecurity. Two case studies are conducted: the use of SeqGAN to generate synthetic network traffic based on the NSL-KDD dataset, and the application of TextGAN to produce realistic malicious PHP code snippets. Each model is evaluated for data fidelity, structural validity, and utility in downstream machine learning tasks. The results demonstrate the potential of GANs to enhance data-driven cybersecurity research and operations by simulating attack scenarios and augmenting limited datasets. Future directions include exploring hybrid models, integrating real-time synthesis, and aligning synthetic data generation with evolving threat intelligence paradigms.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Steinel2025</b:Tag>
		<b:Publisher>PIONEER INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY, NAIROBI, K. E. N. Y. A.</b:Publisher>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>GAN,SeqGAN,TextGAN,cyeersecurity,generative adversarial networks,intrusion detection,synthetic data</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:BookTitle>2025 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON CONVERGENT AND SMART SYSTEMS (ICCSS 2025)</b:BookTitle>
		<b:URL>https://www.wpunj.edu/cosh/macs-scholars-program/assets/SyntheticData.pdf</b:URL>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Steinel</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>B.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Ricky</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Lim</b:Last>
						<b:First>Kiho</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Ku</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>S.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Cyril</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>June</b:Month>
		<b:ConferenceName>2025 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON CONVERGENT AND SMART SYSTEMS (ICCSS 2025)</b:ConferenceName>
		<b:RefOrder>5</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2024</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>techreport</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>Report</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Synthetic data generation for training ai models in web security contexts</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>The increasing complexity and frequency of cyber-attacks necessitate advanced threat detection systems capable of identifying novel and sophisticated intrusions. However, the scarcity of labeled attack data poses significant challenges for training robust AI models in web security contexts. This study explores the generation of realistic synthetic data representing diverse cyber-attack scenarios to augment existing datasets for training AI-driven threat detection systems. Leveraging generative models and domain-specific knowledge, the synthetic data aims to emulate the statistical and behavioral characteristics of real-world attacks while preserving data diversity and complexity. The research evaluates the effectiveness of synthetic attack scenarios in improving model generalization, detection accuracy, and resilience against emerging threats. Results demonstrate that incorporating synthetic data significantly enhances AI models' ability to detect previously unseen attack patterns, thereby strengthening web security defenses. This approach presents a promising avenue for overcoming data limitations and advancing proactive cybersecurity measures.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Cate2024</b:Tag>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>AI Training Data,Anomaly Detection,Artificial Intelligence,Cyber-Attack Simulation,Cybersecurity,Data Augmentation,Generative Models,Intrusion Detection Systems,Machine Learning,Synthetic Data Generation,Threat Detection,Web Security</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:URL>https://www.researchgate.net/publication/392518778_Synthetic_Data_Generation_for_Training_AI_Models_in_Web_Security_Contexts</b:URL>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Cate</b:Last>
						<b:First>Mia</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Sai'</b:Last>
						<b:First>Zaynab</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:ThesisType>Tech. rep.</b:ThesisType>
		<b:RefOrder>16</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2024</b:Year>
		<b:Volume>60</b:Volume>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>book</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Machine learning for cyber physical system: advances and challenges</b:Title>
		<b:Publisher>Switzerland, Springer Nature</b:Publisher>
		<b:Tag>Nayak2024</b:Tag>
		<b:DOI>10.1007/978-3-031-54038-7</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Nayak</b:Last>
						<b:First>Janmenjoy</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
			<b:Editor>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Nayak</b:Last>
						<b:First>Janmenjoy</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Naik</b:Last>
						<b:First>Bighnaraj</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>S</b:Last>
						<b:First>Vimal</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Favorskaya</b:Last>
						<b:First>Margarita</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Editor>
		</b:Author>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISBN: 978-3-031-54037-0</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:RefOrder>17</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Issue>4</b:Issue>
		<b:Year>2024</b:Year>
		<b:Volume>56</b:Volume>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>A survey of privacy attacks in machine learning</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>&lt;p&gt;As machine learning becomes more widely used, the need to study its implications in security and privacy becomes more urgent. Although the body of work in privacy has been steadily growing over the past few years, research on the privacy aspects of machine learning has received less focus than the security aspects. Our contribution in this research is an analysis of more than 45 papers related to privacy attacks against machine learning that have been published during the past seven years. We propose an attack taxonomy, together with a threat model that allows the categorization of different attacks based on the adversarial knowledge, and the assets under attack. An initial exploration of the causes of privacy leaks is presented, as well as a detailed analysis of the different attacks. Finally, we present an overview of the most commonly proposed defenses and a discussion of the open problems and future directions identified during our analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Rigaki2024</b:Tag>
		<b:Publisher>for Computing Machinery, Association</b:Publisher>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>Privacy,machine learning,membership inference,model extraction,model inversion,property inference,reconstruction</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:DOI>10.1145/3624010</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Rigaki</b:Last>
						<b:First>Maria</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Garcia</b:Last>
						<b:First>Sebastian</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>1–34</b:Pages>
		<b:Month>April</b:Month>
		<b:JournalName>ACM Computing Surveys</b:JournalName>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISSN: 0360-0300</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:RefOrder>14</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2023</b:Year>
		<b:Volume>11</b:Volume>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>A comprehensive survey of generative adversarial networks (gans) in cybersecurity intrusion detection</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) have seen significant interest since their introduction in 2014. While originally focused primarily on image-based tasks, their capacity for generating new, synthetic data has brought them into many different fields of Machine Learning research. Their use in cybersecurity has grown swiftly, especially in tasks which require training on unbalanced datasets of attack classes. In this paper we examine the use of GANs in Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS) and how they are currently being employed in this area of research. GANs are currently in use for the creation of adversarial examples, editing the semantic information of data, creating polymorphic samples of malware, augmenting data for rare classes, and much more. We have endeavored to create a paper that may act as a primer for cybersecurity specialists and machine learning researchers alike. This paper details what GANs are and how they work, the current types of GAN in use in the area, datasets used in this research, metrics for evaluation, current areas of use in intrusion detection, and when and how they are best used.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Dunmore2023</b:Tag>
		<b:Publisher>of Electrical, Institute and (IEEE), Electronics Engineers</b:Publisher>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>Generative adversarial networks (GAN),adversarial examples,attack modeling,data augmentation,intrusion detection systems,machine learning,research survey,threat detection,zero-day attacks</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:URL>https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10187144/</b:URL>
		<b:DOI>10.1109/access.2023.3296707</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Dunmore</b:Last>
						<b:First>Aeryn</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Jang-Jaccard</b:Last>
						<b:First>Julian</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Sabrina</b:Last>
						<b:First>Fariza</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Kwak</b:Last>
						<b:First>Jin</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>76071–76094</b:Pages>
		<b:JournalName>IEEE Access</b:JournalName>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISSN: 2169-3536</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:RefOrder>3</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2022</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Red teaming language models to reduce harms: methods, scaling behaviors, and lessons learned</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>We describe our early efforts to red team language models in order to simultaneously discover, measure, and attempt to reduce their potentially harmful outputs. We make three main contributions. First, we investigate scaling behaviors for red teaming across 3 model sizes (2.7B, 13B, and 52B parameters) and 4 model types: a plain language model (LM); an LM prompted to be helpful, honest, and harmless; an LM with rejection sampling; and a model trained to be helpful and harmless using reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF). We find that the RLHF models are increasingly difficult to red team as they scale, and we find a flat trend with scale for the other model types. Second, we release our dataset of 38,961 red team attacks for others to analyze and learn from. We provide our own analysis of the data and find a variety of harmful outputs, which range from offensive language to more subtly harmful non-violent unethical outputs. Third, we exhaustively describe our instructions, processes, statistical methodologies, and uncertainty about red teaming. We hope that this transparency accelerates our ability to work together as a community in order to develop shared norms, practices, and technical standards for how to red team language models.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Ganguli2022</b:Tag>
		<b:DOI>10.48550/ARXIV.2209.07858</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Ganguli</b:Last>
						<b:First>Deep</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Lovitt</b:Last>
						<b:First>Liane</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Kernion</b:Last>
						<b:First>Jackson</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Askell</b:Last>
						<b:First>Amanda</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Bai</b:Last>
						<b:First>Yuntao</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Kadavath</b:Last>
						<b:First>Saurav</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Mann</b:Last>
						<b:First>Ben</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Perez</b:Last>
						<b:First>Ethan</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Schiefer</b:Last>
						<b:First>Nicholas</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Ndousse</b:Last>
						<b:First>Kamal</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Jones</b:Last>
						<b:First>Andy</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Bowman</b:Last>
						<b:First>Sam</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Chen</b:Last>
						<b:First>Anna</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Conerly</b:Last>
						<b:First>Tom</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>DasSarma</b:Last>
						<b:First>Nova</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Drain</b:Last>
						<b:First>Dawn</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Elhage</b:Last>
						<b:First>Nelson</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>El-Showk</b:Last>
						<b:First>Sheer</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Fort</b:Last>
						<b:First>Stanislav</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Hatfield-Dodds</b:Last>
						<b:First>Zac</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Henighan</b:Last>
						<b:First>Tom</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Hernandez</b:Last>
						<b:First>Danny</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Hume</b:Last>
						<b:First>Tristan</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Jacobson</b:Last>
						<b:First>Josh</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Johnston</b:Last>
						<b:First>Scott</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Kravec</b:Last>
						<b:First>Shauna</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Olsson</b:Last>
						<b:First>Catherine</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Ringer</b:Last>
						<b:First>Sam</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Tran-Johnson</b:Last>
						<b:First>Eli</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Amodei</b:Last>
						<b:First>Dario</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Brown</b:Last>
						<b:First>Tom</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Joseph</b:Last>
						<b:First>Nicholas</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>McCandlish</b:Last>
						<b:First>Sam</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Olah</b:Last>
						<b:First>Chris</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Kaplan</b:Last>
						<b:First>Jared</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Clark</b:Last>
						<b:First>Jack</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>November</b:Month>
		<b:RefOrder>7</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2022</b:Year>
		<b:Volume>10</b:Volume>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Evaluation of synthetic data generation techniques in the domain of anonymous traffic classification</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>Anonymous network traffic is more pervasive than ever due to the accessibility of services such as virtual private networks (VPN) and The Onion Router (Tor). To address the need to identify and classify this traffic, machine and deep learning solutions have become the standard. However, high-performing classifiers often scale poorly when applied to real-world traffic classification due to the heavily skewed nature of network traffic data. Prior research has found synthetic data generation to be effective at alleviating concerns surrounding class imbalance, though a limited number of these techniques have been applied to the domain of anonymous network traffic detection. This work compares the ability of a Conditional Tabular Generative Adversarial Network (CTGAN), Copula Generative Adversarial Network (CopulaGAN), Variational Autoencoder (VAE), and Synthetic Minority Over-sampling Technique (SMOTE) to create viable synthetic anonymous network traffic samples. Moreover, we evaluate the performance of several shallow boosting and bagging classifiers as well as deep learning models on the synthetic data. Ultimately, we amalgamate the data generated by the GANs, VAE, and SMOTE into a comprehensive dataset dubbed CMU-SynTraffic-2022 for future research on this topic. Our findings show that SMOTE consistently outperformed the other upsampling techniques, improving classifiers' F1-scores over the control by 7.5% for application type characterization. Among the tested classifiers, Light Gradient Boosting Machine achieved the highest F1-score of 90.3% on eight application types.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Cullen2022</b:Tag>
		<b:Publisher>of Electrical, Institute and Inc., Electronics Engineers</b:Publisher>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>Anonymous traffic,CTGAN,CopulaGAN,SMOTE,TabNet,VAE,deep learning,machine learning,synthetic data,unbalanced data</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:URL>https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9980373/</b:URL>
		<b:DOI>10.1109/access.2022.3228507</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Cullen</b:Last>
						<b:First>Drake</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Halladay</b:Last>
						<b:First>James</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Briner</b:Last>
						<b:First>Nathan</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Basnet</b:Last>
						<b:First>Ram</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Bergen</b:Last>
						<b:First>Jeremy</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Doleck</b:Last>
						<b:First>Tenzin</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>129612–129625</b:Pages>
		<b:JournalName>IEEE Access</b:JournalName>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISSN: 2169-3536</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:RefOrder>6</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2021</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>inproceedings</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>ConferenceProceedings</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Improved denoising diffusion probabilistic models</b:Title>
		<b:Tag>Nichol2021</b:Tag>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Nichol</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>Q.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>A.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Dhariwal</b:Last>
						<b:First>P.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:RefOrder>18</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2020</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Toward trustworthy ai development: mechanisms for supporting verifiable claims</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>With the recent wave of progress in artificial intelligence (AI) has come a growing awareness of the large-scale impacts of AI systems, and recognition that existing regulations and norms in industry and academia are insufficient to ensure responsible AI development. In order for AI developers to earn trust from system users, customers, civil society, governments, and other stakeholders that they are building AI responsibly, they will need to make verifiable claims to which they can be held accountable. Those outside of a given organization also need effective means of scrutinizing such claims. This report suggests various steps that different stakeholders can take to improve the verifiability of claims made about AI systems and their associated development processes, with a focus on providing evidence about the safety, security, fairness, and privacy protection of AI systems. We analyze ten mechanisms for this purpose–spanning institutions, software, and hardware–and make recommendations aimed at implementing, exploring, or improving those mechanisms.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Brundage2020</b:Tag>
		<b:DOI>10.48550/arxiv.2004.07213</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Brundage</b:Last>
						<b:First>Miles</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Avin</b:Last>
						<b:First>Shahar</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Wang</b:Last>
						<b:First>Jasmine</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Belfield</b:Last>
						<b:First>Haydn</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Krueger</b:Last>
						<b:First>Gretchen</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Hadfield</b:Last>
						<b:First>Gillian</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Khlaaf</b:Last>
						<b:First>Heidy</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Yang</b:Last>
						<b:First>Jingying</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Toner</b:Last>
						<b:First>Helen</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Fong</b:Last>
						<b:First>Ruth</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Maharaj</b:Last>
						<b:First>Tegan</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Koh</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>Wei</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Pang</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Hooker</b:Last>
						<b:First>Sara</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Leung</b:Last>
						<b:First>Jade</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Trask</b:Last>
						<b:First>Andrew</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Bluemke</b:Last>
						<b:First>Emma</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Lebensold</b:Last>
						<b:First>Jonathan</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>O'Keefe</b:Last>
						<b:First>Cullen</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Koren</b:Last>
						<b:First>Mark</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Ryffel</b:Last>
						<b:First>Théo</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Rubinovitz</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>B.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>J.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Besiroglu</b:Last>
						<b:First>Tamay</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Carugati</b:Last>
						<b:First>Federica</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Clark</b:Last>
						<b:First>Jack</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Eckersley</b:Last>
						<b:First>Peter</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>de Haas</b:Last>
						<b:First>Sarah</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Johnson</b:Last>
						<b:First>Maritza</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Laurie</b:Last>
						<b:First>Ben</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Ingerman</b:Last>
						<b:First>Alex</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Krawczuk</b:Last>
						<b:First>Igor</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Askell</b:Last>
						<b:First>Amanda</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Cammarota</b:Last>
						<b:First>Rosario</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Lohn</b:Last>
						<b:First>Andrew</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Krueger</b:Last>
						<b:First>David</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Stix</b:Last>
						<b:First>Charlotte</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Henderson</b:Last>
						<b:First>Peter</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Graham</b:Last>
						<b:First>Logan</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Prunkl</b:Last>
						<b:First>Carina</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Martin</b:Last>
						<b:First>Bianca</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Seger</b:Last>
						<b:First>Elizabeth</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Zilberman</b:Last>
						<b:First>Noa</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>hÉigeartaigh</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>Ó.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Seán</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Kroeger</b:Last>
						<b:First>Frens</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Sastry</b:Last>
						<b:First>Girish</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Kagan</b:Last>
						<b:First>Rebecca</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Weller</b:Last>
						<b:First>Adrian</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Tse</b:Last>
						<b:First>Brian</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Barnes</b:Last>
						<b:First>Elizabeth</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Dafoe</b:Last>
						<b:First>Allan</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Scharre</b:Last>
						<b:First>Paul</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Herbert-Voss</b:Last>
						<b:First>Ariel</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Rasser</b:Last>
						<b:First>Martijn</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Sodhani</b:Last>
						<b:First>Shagun</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Flynn</b:Last>
						<b:First>Carrick</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Gilbert</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>Krendl</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Thomas</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Dyer</b:Last>
						<b:First>Lisa</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Khan</b:Last>
						<b:First>Saif</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Bengio</b:Last>
						<b:First>Yoshua</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Anderljung</b:Last>
						<b:First>Markus</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>April</b:Month>
		<b:RefOrder>12</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2019</b:Year>
		<b:Volume>86</b:Volume>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>A survey of network-based intrusion detection data sets</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>Labeled data sets are necessary to train and evaluate anomaly-based network intrusion detection systems. This work provides a focused literature survey of data sets for network-based intrusion detection and describes the underlying packet- and flow-based network data in detail. The paper identifies 15 different properties to assess the suitability of individual data sets for specific evaluation scenarios. These properties cover a wide range of criteria and are grouped into five categories such as data volume or recording environment for offering a structured search. Based on these properties, a comprehensive overview of existing data sets is given. This overview also highlights the peculiarities of each data set. Furthermore, this work briefly touches upon other sources for network-based data such as traffic generators and data repositories. Finally, we discuss our observations and provide some recommendations for the use and the creation of network-based data sets.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Ring2019</b:Tag>
		<b:Publisher>Elsevier, B. V.</b:Publisher>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>Intrusion detection, IDS, NIDS, Data sets, Evaluation, Data mining</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:URL>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S016740481930118X</b:URL>
		<b:DOI>10.1016/j.cose.2019.06.005</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Ring</b:Last>
						<b:First>Markus</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Wunderlich</b:Last>
						<b:First>Sarah</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Scheuring</b:Last>
						<b:First>Deniz</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Landes</b:Last>
						<b:First>Dieter</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Hotho</b:Last>
						<b:First>Andreas</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>147–167</b:Pages>
		<b:Month>September</b:Month>
		<b:JournalName>Computers and Security</b:JournalName>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISSN: 0167-4048</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:RefOrder>1</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2018</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>book</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Security and privacy in cyber-physical systems : foundations, principles, and applications</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>First edition. A source of information on CPS security and privacy theory, guiding principles, and state-of-the-art applications. Written by a team of experts at the forefront of the cyber-physical systems (CPS) revolution, this book provides an in-depth look at security and privacy, two of the most critical challenges facing both the CPS research and development community and ICT professionals. It explores, in depth, the key technical, social, and legal issues at stake, and it provides readers with the information they need to advance research and development in this exciting area. Cyber-physical systems (CPS) are engineered systems that are built from, and depend upon the seamless integration of computational algorithms and physical components. Advances in CPS will enable capability, adaptability, scalability, resiliency, safety, security, and usability far in excess of what simple embedded systems can provide. Just as the Internet revolutionized the way we interact with information, CPS technology has already begun to transform the way people interact with engineered systems. In the years ahead, smart CPS will drive innovation and competition across industry sectors, from agriculture, energy, and transportation, to architecture, healthcare, and manufacturing. This is a long-awaited review for all those concerned with the fundamental concepts and the state-of-the-art in security and privacy in CPS. This book provides comprehensive coverage of the technical issues affecting hardware and software in infrastructure components, as well as the blending of such systems with personal CPS. The contributors discuss various application domains, including energy, medicine, transportation, physical infrastructure, agriculture, smart cities, and many more. The book includes case studies and tutorials and supports university courses such as those in cybersecurity and privacy and CPS engineering and programming. A source of practical information and inspiration, this book will be of use in ongoing RandD and education at the confluence of security, privacy, and CPS. Overview of security and privacy in cyber-physical systems – Network security and privacy for cyber-physical systems – Tutorial on information theoretic metrics quantifying privacy in cyber-physical systems – Cyber-physical systems and national security concerns – Legal considerations of cyber-physical systems and the Internet of Things – Key management in CPSs – Secure registration and remote attestation of IoT devices joining the cloud : the Stack4Things case of study – Context awareness for adaptive access control management in IoT environments – Data privacy issues in distributed security monitoring systems – Privacy protection for cloud-based robotic networks – Toward network coding for cyber-physical systems : security challenges and applications – Lightweight crypto and security – Cyber-physical vulnerabilities of wireless sensor networks in smart cities – Detecting data integrity attacks in smart grid – Data security and privacy in cyber-physical systems for healthcare – Cyber security of smart buildings – The internet of postal things : making the postal infrastructure smarter – Security and privacy issues in the internet of cows – Admission control-based load protection in the smart grid.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.</b:Publisher>
		<b:Tag>Song2018</b:Tag>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Song</b:Last>
						<b:First>Houbing.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Fink</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>A..</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Glenn</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Jeschke</b:Last>
						<b:First>Sabina.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>437</b:Pages>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISBN: 9781119226079</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:RefOrder>19</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:BIBTEX_Copyright>arXiv.org perpetual, non-exclusive license</b:BIBTEX_Copyright>
		<b:Year>2018</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Series>IJCAI-2018</b:BIBTEX_Series>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Agi safety literature review</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>The development of Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) promises to be a major event. Along with its many potential benefits, it also raises serious safety concerns (Bostrom, 2014). The intention of this paper is to provide an easily accessible and up-to-date collection of references for the emerging field of AGI safety. A significant number of safety problems for AGI have been identified. We list these, and survey recent research on solving them. We also cover works on how best to think of AGI from the limited knowledge we have today, predictions for when AGI will first be created, and what will happen after its creation. Finally, we review the current public policy on AGI.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Everitt2018</b:Tag>
		<b:Publisher>arXiv</b:Publisher>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>Artificial Intelligence (cs.AI), FOS: Computer and information sciences</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:BookTitle>Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</b:BookTitle>
		<b:DOI>10.24963/ijcai.2018/768</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Everitt</b:Last>
						<b:First>Tom</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Lea</b:Last>
						<b:First>Gary</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Hutter</b:Last>
						<b:First>Marcus</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>5441–5449</b:Pages>
		<b:Month>July</b:Month>
		<b:ConferenceName>Proceedings of the Twenty-Seventh International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence</b:ConferenceName>
		<b:RefOrder>20</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:BIBTEX_Copyright>arXiv.org perpetual, non-exclusive license</b:BIBTEX_Copyright>
		<b:Year>2017</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Wasserstein gan</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>We introduce a new algorithm named WGAN, an alternative to traditional GAN training. In this new model, we show that we can improve the stability of learning, get rid of problems like mode collapse, and provide meaningful learning curves useful for debugging and hyperparameter searches. Furthermore, we show that the corresponding optimization problem is sound, and provide extensive theoretical work highlighting the deep connections to other distances between distributions.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Arjovsky2017</b:Tag>
		<b:Publisher>arXiv</b:Publisher>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>Machine Learning (stat.ML), Machine Learning (cs.LG), FOS: Computer and information sciences</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:DOI>10.48550/ARXIV.1701.07875</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Arjovsky</b:Last>
						<b:First>Martin</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Chintala</b:Last>
						<b:First>Soumith</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Bottou</b:Last>
						<b:First>Léon</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>January</b:Month>
		<b:RefOrder>9</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:BIBTEX_Copyright>arXiv.org perpetual, non-exclusive license</b:BIBTEX_Copyright>
		<b:Year>2017</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Towards a rigorous science of interpretable machine learning</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>As machine learning systems become ubiquitous, there has been a surge of interest in interpretable machine learning: systems that provide explanation for their outputs. These explanations are often used to qualitatively assess other criteria such as safety or non-discrimination. However, despite the interest in interpretability, there is very little consensus on what interpretable machine learning is and how it should be measured. In this position paper, we first define interpretability and describe when interpretability is needed (and when it is not). Next, we suggest a taxonomy for rigorous evaluation and expose open questions towards a more rigorous science of interpretable machine learning.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>DoshiVelez2017</b:Tag>
		<b:Publisher>arXiv</b:Publisher>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>Machine Learning (stat.ML), Artificial Intelligence (cs.AI), Machine Learning (cs.LG), FOS: Computer and information sciences</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:URL>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/5c39e37022661f81f79e481240ed9b175dec6513</b:URL>
		<b:DOI>10.48550/ARXIV.1702.08608</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Doshi-Velez</b:Last>
						<b:First>Finale</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Kim</b:Last>
						<b:First>Been</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>February</b:Month>
		<b:RefOrder>21</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2017</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Series>KDD ’17</b:BIBTEX_Series>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>inproceedings</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>ConferenceProceedings</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Machine learning for encrypted malware traffic classification: accounting for noisy labels and non-stationarity</b:Title>
		<b:Tag>Anderson2017</b:Tag>
		<b:Publisher>ACM</b:Publisher>
		<b:BookTitle>Proceedings of the 23rd ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</b:BookTitle>
		<b:URL>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/37453d54ee3d8f65f7b201215b264060456ede10</b:URL>
		<b:DOI>10.1145/3097983.3098163</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Anderson</b:Last>
						<b:First>Blake</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>McGrew</b:Last>
						<b:First>David</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>1723–1732</b:Pages>
		<b:Month>August</b:Month>
		<b:ConferenceName>Proceedings of the 23rd ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining</b:ConferenceName>
		<b:RefOrder>2</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2015</b:Year>
		<b:Volume>521</b:Volume>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>article</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>JournalArticle</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Deep learning</b:Title>
		<b:Tag>LeCun2015</b:Tag>
		<b:Publisher>Science, Springer and Business Media, L. L. C.</b:Publisher>
		<b:DOI>10.1038/nature14539</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>LeCun</b:Last>
						<b:First>Yann</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Bengio</b:Last>
						<b:First>Yoshua</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Hinton</b:Last>
						<b:First>Geoffrey</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>436–444</b:Pages>
		<b:Month>May</b:Month>
		<b:JournalName>Nature</b:JournalName>
		<b:Number>7553</b:Number>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISSN: 1476-4687</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:RefOrder>22</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2014</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>book</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:Comments>Auf dem Buchdeckel: "Dr. Dobbs Jolt Award Finalist 2014"</b:Comments>
		<b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Threat modeling</b:Title>
		<b:Tag>Shostack2014</b:Tag>
		<b:Publisher>Wiley</b:Publisher>
		<b:URL>https://books.google.com/books?id=asPDAgAAQBAJ</b:URL>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Shostack</b:Last>
						<b:First>Adam</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISBN: 9781118809990LCCN: 2013954095</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:City>Indianapolis</b:City>
		<b:StateProvince>IN</b:StateProvince>
		<b:RefOrder>11</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2014</b:Year>
		<b:Volume>27</b:Volume>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>inproceedings</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>ConferenceProceedings</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Generative adversarial nets</b:Title>
		<b:Publisher>Curran Associates, Inc.</b:Publisher>
		<b:Tag>Goodfellow2014</b:Tag>
		<b:BookTitle>Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</b:BookTitle>
		<b:URL>https://proceedings.neurips.cc/paper_files/paper/2014/file/f033ed80deb0234979a61f95710dbe25-Paper.pdf</b:URL>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Goodfellow</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>J.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Ian</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Pouget-Abadie</b:Last>
						<b:First>Jean</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Mirza</b:Last>
						<b:First>Mehdi</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Xu</b:Last>
						<b:First>Bing</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Warde-Farley</b:Last>
						<b:First>David</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Ozair</b:Last>
						<b:First>Sherjil</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Courville</b:Last>
						<b:First>Aaron</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Bengio</b:Last>
						<b:First>Yoshua</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
			<b:Editor>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Ghahramani</b:Last>
						<b:First>Z.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Welling</b:Last>
						<b:First>M.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Cortes</b:Last>
						<b:First>C.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Lawrence</b:Last>
						<b:First>N.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Weinberger</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>Q.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>K.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Editor>
		</b:Author>
		<b:ConferenceName>Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems</b:ConferenceName>
		<b:RefOrder>8</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Department>National Institute of Standards and Technology</b:Department>
		<b:Year>2012</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>techreport</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>Report</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Guide for conducting risk assessments</b:Title>
		<b:Tag>Blank2012</b:Tag>
		<b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>Cost-benefit analysis,Risk concept,Risk determination,Risk management,SP 800-30,SP 800-30 Revision 1,Security controls,System vulnerabilities,residual risk,risk,risk assessment,risk management,risk mitigation,security controls,threat vulnerability</b:BIBTEX_KeyWords>
		<b:URL>https://csrc.nist.gov/pubs/sp/800/30/r1/final</b:URL>
		<b:DOI>10.6028/NIST.SP.800-30r1</b:DOI>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Blank</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>M.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Rebecca</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Gallagher</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>D.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Patrick</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>September</b:Month>
		<b:ThesisType>Tech. rep.</b:ThesisType>
		<b:RefOrder>10</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2010</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>inproceedings</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>ConferenceProceedings</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Modeling cyber-insurance: towards a unifying framework</b:Title>
		<b:Tag>Boehme2010</b:Tag>
		<b:BookTitle>Workshop on the Economics of Information Security</b:BookTitle>
		<b:URL>https://api.semanticscholar.org/CorpusID:14172008</b:URL>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Böhme</b:Last>
						<b:First>Rainer</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Schwartz</b:Last>
						<b:First>Galina</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:ConferenceName>Workshop on the Economics of Information Security</b:ConferenceName>
		<b:RefOrder>23</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2010</b:Year>
		<b:Volume>1</b:Volume>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>book</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Advances in artificial intelligence for privacy protection and security</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>In this book, we aim to collect the most recent advances in artificial intelligence techniques (i.e. neural networks, fuzzy systems, multi-agent systems, genetic algorithms, image analysis, clustering, etc), which are applied to the protection of privacy and security. The symbiosis between these fields leads to a pool of invigorating ideas, which are explored in this book. On the one hand, individual privacy protection is a hot topic and must be addressed in order to guarantee the proper evolution of a modern society. On the other, security can invade individual privacy, especially after the. Preface; 1. Introduction A. Solanas and A. Martnez-Balleste; 1.1. Organization of the book; References; PART 1: A Brief Introduction to Privacy and Security; 2. An Introduction to Privacy Aspects of Information and Communication Technologies A. Martinez-Balleste and A. Solanas; Contents; 2.1. Introduction; 2.2. Privacy and the Internet; 2.2.1. Monitoring User Activity; 2.2.1.1. Tracking Cookies; 2.2.1.2. Spyware; 2.2.1.3. Social Engineering Attacks; 2.2.2. Privacy in Modern Web Services; 2.2.2.1. Privacy in Social Networks; 2.2.2.2. Privacy in E-Commerce</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Publisher>Scientific, World</b:Publisher>
		<b:Tag>Ruan2010</b:Tag>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Ruan</b:Last>
						<b:First>Da</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Xu</b:Last>
						<b:First>Jun</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Lu</b:Last>
						<b:First>Jie</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
			<b:Editor>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Solanas</b:Last>
						<b:First>Agusti.</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Martínez-Ballesté</b:Last>
						<b:First>Antoni</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Editor>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>391</b:Pages>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISBN: 9812790322</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:RefOrder>24</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>2009</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>book</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:Comments>Literaturverz. S. [425] - 451</b:Comments>
		<b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>An introduction to multiagent systems</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>2nd ed. This book will introduce students to intelligent agents, explain what these agents are, how they are constructed and how they can be made to co-operate effectively with one another in large-scale systems. Intelligent Agents – Deductive Reasoning Agents – Practical Reasoning Agents – Reactive and Hybrid Agents – Understanding Each Other – Communicating – Working Together – Methodologies – Applications – Multiagent Interactions – Making Group Decisions – Forming Coalitions – Allocating Scarce Resources – Bargaining – Arguing – Logical Foundations.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Wooldridge2009</b:Tag>
		<b:Publisher>Sons, John Wiley &amp;</b:Publisher>
		<b:Edition>second</b:Edition>
		<b:URL>https://uranos.ch/research/references/Wooldridge_2001/TLTK.pdf https://www.wiley.com/en-be/An+Introduction+to+MultiAgent+Systems%2C+2nd+Edition-p-9780470519462 https://www.amazon.com/Introduction-MultiAgent-Systems-Michael-Wooldridge/dp/047149691X</b:URL>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Wooldridge</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>J.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Michael</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Pages>461</b:Pages>
		<b:Month>May</b:Month>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISBN: 9780470519462</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:City>Chichester</b:City>
		<b:RefOrder>13</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:Year>1992</b:Year>
		<b:BIBTEX_Series>A Bradford book</b:BIBTEX_Series>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>book</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>Book</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Reinforcement learning</b:Title>
		<b:BIBTEX_Abstract>The significantly expanded and updated new edition of a widely used text on reinforcement learning, one of the most active research areas in artificial intelligence. Reinforcement learning, one of the most active research areas in artificial intelligence, is a computational approach to learning whereby an agent tries to maximize the total amount of reward it receives while interacting with a complex, uncertain environment. In Reinforcement Learning, Richard Sutton and Andrew Barto provide a clear and simple account of the field's key ideas and algorithms. This second edition has been significantly expanded and updated, presenting new topics and updating coverage of other topics.

Like the first edition, this second edition focuses on core online learning algorithms, with the more mathematical material set off in shaded boxes. Part I covers as much of reinforcement learning as possible without going beyond the tabular case for which exact solutions can be found. Many algorithms presented in this part are new to the second edition, including UCB, Expected Sarsa, and Double Learning. Part II extends these ideas to function approximation, with new sections on such topics as artificial neural networks and the Fourier basis, and offers expanded treatment of off-policy learning and policy-gradient methods. Part III has new chapters on reinforcement learning's relationships to psychology and neuroscience, as well as an updated case-studies chapter including AlphaGo and AlphaGo Zero, Atari game playing, and IBM Watson's wagering strategy. The final chapter discusses the future societal impacts of reinforcement learning.</b:BIBTEX_Abstract>
		<b:Tag>Sutton1992</b:Tag>
		<b:Publisher>Press, M. I. T.</b:Publisher>
		<b:Edition>second</b:Edition>
		<b:URL>https://web.stanford.edu/class/psych209/Readings/SuttonBartoIPRLBook2ndEd.pdf https://mitpress.ublish.com/ebook/reinforcement-learning-an-introduction-2-preview/2351/viii</b:URL>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Sutton</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>S.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Richard</b:First>
					</b:Person>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Barto</b:Last>
						<b:Middle>G.</b:Middle>
						<b:First>Andrew</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
			<b:Editor>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>Barto</b:Last>
						<b:First>Andrew</b:First>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Editor>
		</b:Author>
		<b:Month>May</b:Month>
		<b:StandardNumber> ISBN: 9780262193986</b:StandardNumber>
		<b:City>Cambridge</b:City>
		<b:StateProvince>Massachusetts</b:StateProvince>
		<b:RefOrder>15</b:RefOrder></b:Source><b:Source>
		<b:BIBTEX_Entry>misc</b:BIBTEX_Entry>
		<b:SourceType>Misc</b:SourceType>
		<b:Title>Gpt-4o system card | openai</b:Title>
		<b:Tag>OpenAI</b:Tag>
		<b:URL>https://openai.com/index/gpt-4o-system-card/</b:URL>
		<b:Author>
			<b:Author>
				<b:NameList>
					<b:Person>
						<b:Last>OpenAI</b:Last>
					</b:Person>
				</b:NameList>
			</b:Author>
		</b:Author>
		<b:PublicationTitle>Gpt-4o system card | openai</b:PublicationTitle>
		<b:RefOrder>25</b:RefOrder></b:Source></b:Sources>
